Wonder by RJ palaso Jack will Julian and Charlotte WE FOLLOWED MR. TUSHMAN into a
small room across from Mrs. Garcia’s desk.
He was talking as he closed the door to his office and sat down behind his big
desk, though I wasn’t really paying much attention to what he was saying. I was
looking around at all the things on his desk. Cool stuff, like a globe floating in
the air and a Rubik's cube made with little mirrors. I liked his office a lot.
I lik that there were all these neat little drawings and paintings by
students on the walls, framed like they were important. Mom sat down in a chair in
front of Mr. Tushman’s desk, and even though there was another chair right
next to hers, I decided to stand beside her. “Why do you have your own room and
Mrs. G doesn’t?” I said. “You mean, why do I have an office?” asked Mr.
Tushman. “You said she runs the place,” I said. “Oh! Well, I was kind of kidding. Mrs. G
is my assistant.” “Mr. Tushman is the director of the middle school,” Mom explained.
“Do they call you Mr. T?” I asked, which made him
smile. “Do you know who Mr. T is?” he answered. “I pity the fool?” he said in a
funny tough voice, like he was imitating someone. I had no idea what he was talking
about. “Anyway, no,” said Mr. Tushman, shaking his head. “No one calls me Mr. T.
Though I have a feeling I’m called a lot
of other things I don’t know about. Let’s
face it, a name like mine is not so easy to live with, you know what I
mean?” Here I have to admit I totally laughed, because I knew exactly what he
meant. “My mom and dad had a teacher called Miss Butt,” I said Augie said Mom,
but Mr. Tushman laughed. “Now that that’s bad,” said Mr. Tushman, shaking his head. “I
guess I shouldn’t complain. Hey, so listen, August, here’s what I thought we would do
today. “Is that a pumpkin?” I said, pointing to a framed painting behind Mr. Tushman’s
desk ay sweetie, don’t interrupt,” said Mom.
“You like it?” said Mr. Tushman, turning around and looking at the painting. “I do, too.
And I thought it was a pumpkin, too, until the student who gave it to me explained
that it is actually not a pumpkin. It is are you ready for this a portrait of me!
Now, August, I ask you: do I really look that much like a
pumpkin?” “No!” I answered, though I was thinking yes. Something about the way his
cheeks puffed out when he smiled made him look like a jackal lantern. Just as I
thought that, it occurred to me how funny that was: cheeks, Mr. Tushman. And I started
laughing a little. I shook my head and covered my mouth with my hand. Mr. Tushman
smiled like he could read my mind. I was about to say something else,
but then all of a sudden I heard other voices outside the office: kids’ voices.
I’m not exaggerating when I say this, but my heart literally started beating like
I just run the longest race in the world a laughter I had inside just poured out
of me. The thing is, when I was little, I never minded beeting new kids because
all the kids I met were really little, too. What’s cool about really little kids
is that they don’t say stuff to try to hurt your feelings, even though sometimes
they do say stuff that hurt your feelings. But they don’t actually know what they’re saying.
Big kids, though: they know what they’re saying. And that is definitely not fun
for me. One of the reasons I grew my hair
long last year was that I like how my bangs cover my eyes: it helps me block
out the things I don’t want to see. Mrs. Garcia knocked on the door and
poked her head inside. “They’re here, Mr.
Tushman,” she said. “Who’s here?” I said that Thanks,” said Mr. Tushman to Mrs. Garcia.
“August, I thought it would be a good idea for you to meet some students who’ll be
in your home room this year. I figure they could take you around the school a
bit, show you the lay of the land, so to
speak.” “I don’t want to meet anyone,” I said to Mom. Mr. Tushman was suddenly right in
front of me, his hands on my shoulders. He leaned down and said very softly in my
ear: “It’ll be okay okay, August. These are nice kids, I promise.” “You’re going to be
okay, Auggie,” Mom whispered with all her might. Before she could say anything else,
Mr. Tushman opened the door to his office.
“Come on in, kids,” he said, and in walked two boys and a girl. None of them looked
over at me or Mom: they stood by the door looking straight at Mr. Tushman like
their lives depended on it.
“Thanks so much for coming, guys— —especially since school doesn’t start
until next month!” said Mr. Tushman. “Have you had a good summer?” All of them nodded
but no one said anything. “Great, great,” said Mr. Tushman. “So, guys, I wanted you to
meet August, who’s going to be a new student here this year. August, these guys
have been students at Beacher Prep since kindergarten, though, of course, they were
in the lower school building, but they know all the ins and outs of the middle
school program. And since you’re all in the same home room I thought it would be
nice if you got to know each other a little before school started. Okay? So,
kids, this is August. August, this is Jack Will.” Jack Will looked at me and put out
his hand. When I shook it, he kind of half smiled and said: “Hey,” and looked down
really fast asked This is Julian,” said Mr.
Tushman. “Hey,” said Julian, and did the same exact thing as Jack Will: took my hand,
forced a smile, looked down fast. “And charlot said Mr. Tushman.
Charlotte had the blondest hair I’ve ever seen. She didn’t shake my hand but
gave me a quick little wave and smiled.
“Hi, August. Nice to meet you,” she said. “Hi,” I said, looking down. She was wearing bright
green Crocs. “So,” said Mr. Tushman, putting his hands together in a kind of slow
clap. “What I thought you guys could do is take August on a little tour of the
school. Maybe you could start on the third floor? That’s where your home room
class is going to be: room 301. I think. Mrs. G, is—” “Room 301!” Mrs. Garcia
called out from the other room. “Room 301.” Mr. Tushman nodded. “And then you can show
August the science labs and the computer room. Then work your way down to the
library and the performance space on the second floor. Take him to the cafeteria,
of course.” “Should we take him to the music room?” asked Julian. “Good idea, yes,”
said Mr. Tushman. “August, do you play any instruments?” “No,” I said. It wasn’t my
favorite subject on account of the fact that I don’t really have ears. Well, I do,
but they don’t exactly look like normal
[Music]
ears. “Well, you may enjoy seeing the music room anyway,” said Mr. Tushman. “We have a
very nice selection of percussion instruments.” “August, you’ve been wanting
to learn to play the drums,” Mom said, trying to get me to look at her. But my
eyes were covered by my bangs as I stared at a piece of old gum that was
stuck to the bottom of Mr. Tushman’s desk.
“Great! Okay, so why don’t you guys get going?” said Mr. Tushman. “Just be back here
in He looked at Mom. “Half an hour, okay?” I think Mom nodded. “So, is that okay with
you, August?” he asked me. I didn’t answer. “Is that okay, August?” Mom repeated.
I looked at her now. I wanted her to see
how mad I was at her. But then I saw her face and just nodded. She seemed more
scared than I was. The other kids had started out the
door, so I followed them. “See you soon,” said Mom, her voice sounding a little higher than
normal. I didn’t answer her The Grand Tour JACK WILL, JULIAN, CHARLOTTE and I
went down a big hallway to some wide stairs. No one said a word as we walked
up to the third floor. When we got to the
top of the stairs, we went down a little hallway full of lots of doors. Julian
opened the door marked 301. “This is our home room he said,
standing in front of the half openen door. “We have Miss Bossa They say she’s
okay, at least for home room I heard she’s really strict if you get her for math,
though.” “That’s not true,” said Charlotte. “My sister had her last year and said she’s totally
nice.” “Not what I heard,” answered Julian, “but whatever.” He closed the door and
continu continued walking down the hallway. “This is the science lab,” he said
when he got to the next door. And just like he did two seconds ago, he stood in
front of the half openen door and started talking. He didn’t look at me
once while he talked, which was okay because I wasn’t looking at him, either.
“You won’t know who you have for science until the first day of school, but you
want to get Mr holler used to be in the lower school.
He would play this giant tuba in class.” “It was a baritone horn,” said Charlotte. “It
was a tuba!” answered Julian, closing the door. “Dude, let him go inside so he can
check it out,” Jack Will told him, pushing past Julian and opening the door. “Go
inside if you want,” Julian said. It was the first time he looked at me. I
shrugged and walked over to the door.
Julian moved out of the way quickly, like he was afraid I might accidentally touch
him as I passed by him. “Nothing much to see,” Julian said, walking in after me. He
started pointing to a bunch of stuff around the room. “That’s the incubator.
That big black thing is the chalkboard. These are the desks. These are chairs. Those are the
buns and burners. This is a gross science poster.
This is chalk. This is the eraser.” “I’m sure he knows when an eraser
is,” Charlotte said, sounding a little like
Via. “How would I know what he knows?” Julian answered. “Mr. Tushman said he’s
never been to a school before.” “You know what an eraser is, right?”
Charlotte asked me. I admit I was feeling so nervous that I didn’t know what to
say or do except look at the floor. “Hey, can you talk?” asked Jack Will.
“Yeah.” I nodded. I still really hadn’t looked at any of them yet, not
directly. “You know what an eraser is, right?” asked Jack Will. “Of course!” I
mumbled. “I told you there was nothing to see in here,” said Julian,
shrugging. “I have a question I said, trying to keep my voice
steady. “Um. What exactly is home room Is that like a subject?” “No, that’s just your group,”
explained Charlotte, ignoring Julian’s smirk. “It’s like where you go when you
get to school in the morning and your home room teacher takes attendance and
stuff like that. In a way, it’s your main class even though it’s not really a
class. I mean, it’s a class, but—” “I think he
gets it, Charlotte,” said jackw Do you get it?” Charlotte asked me. “Yeah.” I nodded at
her. “Okay, let’s get out of here,” said Jack Will, walking
away. “Wait, Jack, we’re supposed to be answering questions,” said Charlotte. Jack
Will rolled his eyes a little as he turned around. “Do you have any more
questions?” he asked. “Um, no,” I answered. “Oh, well, actually, yes. Is your name Jack or
Jack Will?” “Jack is my first name. Will is my last name.” “Oh, because Mr. Tushman introduced
you as Jack Will, so I thought You thought his name was was Jack will laughed
Juliet Yeah, some people call me by my first and last name,” Jack said, shrugging.
“I don’t know why. Anyway, can we go now?” “Let’s go to the performance space next,”
said Charlotte, leading the way out of the science room. “It’s very cool. You’ll like it,
August the performance space CHARLOTTE BASICALLY DIDN’T stop
talking as we headed down to the second floor. She was describing the play they
had put on last year, which was Oliver!
She played Oliver even though she’s a girl. As she said this, she pushed open
the double doors to a huge auditorium. At the other end of the room
was a stage. Charlotte started skipping toward the stage. Julian ran after her,
and then turned around halfway down the
[Music]
aisle. “Come on!” he said loudly, waving for me to follow him, which I
did. “There were like hundreds of people in the audience that night,” said
Charlotte, and it took me a second to realize she was still talking about
Oliver! “I was so, so nervous. I had so many
lines, and I had all these songs to sing.
It was so, so, so, so hard!” Although she was
talking to me, she really didn’t look at me much. “On opening night, my parents were
all the way in the back of the auditorium, like where Jack is right now,
but when the lights are off, you can’t really see that far back. So I was like,
‘Where are my parents? Where are my parents?’ And then Mr Resnik our Theater
Arts teacher last year— —he said: ‘Charlotte, stop being such a diva!’ And I was like,
‘Okay!’ And then I spotted my parents and I was totally fine. I didn’t forget a single
line.” While she was talking, I noticed Julian staring at me out of the corner
of his eye. This is something I see people do a lot with me. They think I
don’t know they’re staring, but I can tell from the way their heads are tilted.
I turned around to see where Jack had gone to. He had stayed in the back of the
auditorium, like he was bored. “We put on a play every every year,” said
Charlotte. “I don’t think he’s going to want to be in the school play, Charlotte,”
said Julian sarcastically. “You can be in the play without being ‘in’ the play,” Charlotte
answered, looking at me. “You can do the lighting. You can paint the
backdrops.” “Oh yeah whoopy said Julian, twirling his finger in the air. “But you
don’t have to take the Theater Arts elective if you don’t want to,” Charlotte said,
shrugging. “There’s dance or chorus or band. There’s leadership.” “Only dorks take leadership,”
Julian interrupted. “Julian, you’re being so obnoxious!” said Charlotte, which made Julian
laugh. “I’m taking the science elective,” I said. “Cool!” said Charlotte. Julian looked
directly at me. “The science elective is probably the hardest elective of all,” he
said. “No offense, but if you’ve never, ever been in a school before, why do you think
you’re suddenly going to be smart enough to take the science elective? I mean, have
you ever even studied science before?
Like real science, not like the kind you do in kids Yeah.” I nodded. “He was homeschooled,
Julian!” said Charlotte. “So teachers came to his house?” asked Julian, looking
puzzled. “No, his mother taught him!” answered Charlotte. “Is she a teacher?”
Julian said. “Is your mother a teacher?” Charlotte asked me. “No,” I said. “So she’s
not a real teacher!” said Julian, as if that proved his point. “That’s what I mean.
How can someone who’s not a real teacher actually teach
science?” “I’m sure you’ll do fine,” said Charlotte, looking at me. “Let’s just go to
the library now,” Jack called out, sounding really bored. “Why is your hair so long?” Julian
said to me. He sounded like he was annoyed. I didn’t know what to say, so I
just shrugged. “Can I ask you a question?” he asked
I shrugged again. Didn’t he just ask me a question? “What’s the deal with your face?
I mean, were you in a fire or something?” “Julian, that’s so rude!” said Charlotte. “I’m
not being rude,” said Julian, “I’m just asking a question. Mr. Tushman said we
could ask questions if we wanted to.” “Not rude questions like that,”
said Charlotte. “Besides, he was born like that. That’s what Mr. Tushman said. You just weren’t
listening.” “I was so listening!” said Julian.
“I just thought maybe he was in a fire, too.” “Geez, Julian,” said Jack. “Just shut up.”
“You shut up!” Julian yelled. “Come on, August,” said Jack. “Let’s just go to the library
already.” I walked toward Jack and followed him out of the auditorium. He
held the double doors open for me, and as
I passed by, he looked at me right in the
face, kind of daring me to look back at him, which I did. Then I actually smiled. I
don’t know. Sometimes when I have the feeling like I’m almost crying, it can
turn into an almost laughing feeling. And that must have been the feeling I was
having then, because I smiled, almost like I was going to giggle. The
thing is, because of the way my face is,
people who don’t know me very well don’t always get that I’m smiling. My mouth
doesn’t go up at the corners the way other people’s mouths do. It just goes
straight across my face. But somehow Jack Will got that I had smiled at him. And he
smiled back. “Julian’s a jerk,” he whispered before Julian and Charlotte reached us.
“But, dude, you’re going to have to talk.” He said this seriously, like he was trying to
help me. I nodded as Julian and Charlotte caught up to us. We were all quiet for a
second, all of us just kind of nodding, looking at the floor. Then I looked up at
Julian. “The word supposedly,’ by the way,” I said are you talking about?” “You said
supposedly before,” I said. “I didn't not!” “Yeah you did,” Charlotte nodded. “You
said the science elective is supposedly really hard. I heard you.” “I absolutely did not,” he
insisted. “Whatever,” said Jack. “Let’s just go.” “Yeah, let’s just go,” agreed Charlotte,
following Jack down the stairs to the next floor. I started to follow her, but
Julian cut right in front of me, which actually made me stumble
backward. “Oops, sorry about that!” said Julian. But I could tell from the way he
looked at me that he wasn’t really sorry at
[Music]
all